Michael R. Dinerstein

Software Engineer, Full Stack Web Applications & Data

Professional Summary

With over 12 years of professional software engineering and web development experience, I love to design and build interactive, informative, and *interesting* software products with a variety of tech. I thrive in a team environment, but can also navigate on my own. I founded <u>openresume.org</u> to learn new things about growing my own platform, and I've contributed to open-source projects such as *Flagsmith* and *WPGraphQL TestCase*.

Work Experience

<u>OpenResume.org</u> - Newport, OR - Sep. 2024 to Present

Founder, Software Engineer

- Created open-source template repository for web and print resume themes.
- Integrated AI assistance to optimize resumes for applications.

The Real Deal - New York, NY (Remote) - Feb. 2022 to Aug. 2024

Senior Full Stack Developer

- Reduced cloud costs by 10% by solving complex caching issues with images, Next.js, CloudFront and Kubernetes.
- Increased confidence in deployments by instilling continuous integration workflows for repositories.
- Enhanced quality and reliability by improving team development practices and code review processes.
- Reduced developer onboarding time from hours to minutes with VS Code Dev Containers and improved docs.
- Streamlined debugging and troubleshooting processes by enabling visibility in all layers of the stack with Sentry.
- Improved stability and performance of the company website with 3+ million monthly visitors.
- Increased address data accuracy to 90% by engineering a robust geocoding solution.
- Fostered cross-team collaboration by developing an internal API to share secure access to data stores.
- Reduced manual testing steps by containerizing automated test suites for use within GitHub Actions.
- Pinpointed performance bottlenecks by configuring containerized JMeter test suites with reporting.

RRFC - Los Angeles, CA (Remote) - Jan. 2014 to Feb. 2022

Lead Developer / Designer - July 2018 to Feb. 2022

- Enhanced productivity for all departments by upgrading Salesforce in partnership with vendors.
- Modernized accounting workflows between learning management systems, Salesforce and QuickBooks.
- Improved website performance and fixed technical SEO issues across multiple websites.
- Streamlined student payments and reduced friction via customized payment portal integrated with Salesforce.
- Prioritized deliverables and managed project timelines by overseeing contract work from vendors.
- Ensured knowledge redundancy by training up and mentoring other developers and designers.
- Increased growth and rate of deployments for new student curriculum.
- Optimized funnels in Salesforce via geo-targeted tier systems and automated workflows.

Web Developer / Designer - Jan. 2016 to July 2018

- Innovated custom learning management systems to tailor the experience to a unique model of education.
- Optimized websites with shared content via proprietary internal API and robust caching mechanism.
- Organized development processes by utilizing version control in GitHub.

Junior Graphic Designer - Jan. 2014 to Jan. 2016

- Digitized print curriculum and modernized the student experience with interactive eBook programming.
- Improved student engagement with custom interactive web exercises (canvas, web audio).

Work Experience

<u>Self-Employed / Freelance</u> - Los Angeles, CA (Remote)

Bridged the gap between business needs and tech solutions for clients in a variety of verticals including
motorsports, legal, beauty, real estate, entertainment, places of worship, television, photography, film, audio
engineering, construction, ecommerce, and education.

Projects

- **TRD News** High-traffic news website and mobile app, worked with international team to migrate WordPress installations to a performant Next.js + headless setup on Kubernetes in AWS: https://therealdeal.com/
- **TRD Data** subscription real estate data access portal. Focused on engineering, but also coordinated efforts between data engineers and researchers, web developers, designers and QA: https://therealdeal.com/data/
- RRFC Student Portal custom learning management system, designed and developed to meet state compliance standards, engage students and monitor progress: https://vimeo.com/285858970
- **RRFC Reviews** API to sync survey responses for marketing and sales purposes, developed to streamline customer feedback into usable marketing materials.
- OpenResume Interactive resume builder with custom open-source theming system:
 www.openresume.org/r/michael-dinerstein and github.com/missionmike/openresume-theme
- **SmashKeys** Does your toddler ever want to mash on the keyboard with you while you're working? Hook them up with this fun page! View the live site on www.smashkeys.org

Open Source

- WPGraphQL Test Case While using this testing library, I encountered an issue and worked closely with the
 original author to fix it: https://github.com/wp-graphgl/wp-graphgl-testcase
- Flagsmith I implemented feature flags for OpenResume.org using Flagsmith.io, and noticed the documentation on the official Flagsmith website didn't include the version of Next.js I was using. After figuring out the setup, I opened a pull request to update the documentation: https://github.com/Flagsmith/flagsmith
- **OpenResume Theme** Public open-source repository to allow users to contribute to the OpenResume.org template system, published on npm: https://www.npmis.com/package/@openresume/theme

Education

Santa Monica College - Santa Monica, CA

- Database Applications Developer, Department Certificate
- Web Programmer, Department Certificate

Technical Skills

Full Stack: Next.js, TypeScript, JavaScript, GraphQL, WordPress, PHP, eCommerce, webpack

Frontend: React, HTML, CSS, SCSS, Tailwind, Bootstrap, MaterialUI, TanStack Query, Accessibility, SEO, Lighthouse, Google Tag Manager, jQuery, GatsbyJS

Backend: Python, Flask, MySQL, MariaDB, PostgreSQL, Node.js, Prisma, SQLAlchemy, Headless WordPress, Redis, MongoDB, DocumentDB, S3, EC2, CloudWatch, SES, Airflow

DevOps: AWS, GCP, DigitalOcean, cPanel, WHM, Docker, Terraform, Kubernetes, GitHub Actions, CI/CD (Continuous Integration and Continuous Delivery), VS Code Dev Containers, Linux

Testing: Jest, PHPUnit, Pytest, Cypress, Selenium, JMeter

Platforms & APIs: Sentry, Salesforce, Pardot, Tableau, Mailchimp, Zapier, Google Maps, Google Analytics